Guide to the Rudd family papers, 1777-1952,
Rudd family papers, 1777-1952.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Rudd family papers, 1777-1952, [ca.1804]-1952 (bulk).
1636
Rudd family.
1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, notes and notebooks, printed material, and other documents.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, notes and notebooks, printed material, and miscellany concerning the family affairs and genealogy of the Rudd, Porter, DeForest, and other related families and including information on the history of Norwich, Connecticut, where the family originated. Of particular interest are a copy of a letter (August 26, 1777) from Joseph Rudd, describing the battle at Bennington, Vermont; two letters (1827) about a religious revival in Huntington, Connecticut; and B. Rudd's book of sketches made in Italy (1891-1894).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, notes and notebooks, printed material, and miscellany concerning the family affairs and genealogy of the Rudd, Porter, DeForest, and other related families and including information on the history of Norwich, Connecticut, where the family originated. Of particular interest are a copy of a letter (August 26, 1777) from Joseph Rudd, describing the battle at Bennington, Vermont; two letters (1827) about a religious revival in Huntington, Connecticut; and B. Rudd's book of sketches made in Italy (1891-1894).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rudd family.; DeForest family.; Porter family.; Rudd, B.; Rudd, Joseph.
Subjects:
Religion.; Revivals.
Places:
United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--Campaigns.; Bennington, Battle of, N.Y., 1777.; Italy.; Norwich (Conn.)--History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1803-1810 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1812-1819 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1820-1828 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1885-1895 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: Mary Ojeti and children Bepi and Vera, 1895-1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1906-1909 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ms. - Ancestry of Margaret Baret, 1915-1922 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miner and Darrow Sage Correspondence re Society of Dames, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Morris Family Genealogy (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Porter Family Genealogy (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- Porter Family Genealogy; also, Huntingyon, Baret, Morris, White Families (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Rudd, De Forest, Shelton Family Genealogies (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Rudd Family Genealogy (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Rudd Family Genealogy (Tracy-Huntington-Porter-Rudd) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Historical Article by George Shepard Porter for The Bulletin (Norwich, Connecticut) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Historical Essay (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Notes: History of Norwich, Connecticut (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Newspaper clippings (mailnly historical subjects), ca. 1904-1907 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Genealogy questions (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Historical/Genealogical Material (Box 2, Folder 6-12)
- The Uncas Monument, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Notebook: Heraldry (Box 3)
- Notebook: "156 names on Soldiers momument" (Box 3)
- Notebook: Porter Genealogy (Box 3)
- Bank book (blank) (Box 3)
- Notebook: Porter, Rudd, etal Genealogies (Box 3)
- Ancestral Tablets (pedigree diagrams): Rudd, Porter etal, 1845 (Box 3)
- Sketchbook: Margaret Blagrove Rudd (Roma), 1891-1993 (Box 3)
- Catalogue of Foreign Ancestries of American Colonial Families by George S. Porter (Box 3)
- Inscrptions from Gravestones in Christ Church, Norwich, Conn. By George S. Porter, 1906 (Box 3)